<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/</id><updated>1984-01-01T01:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>crestwindfallen</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/crestwindfallen.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>1984-01-01T01:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>ibowman</name></author><id>tag:ibowman.com,1984-01-01:theironedcurtain/crestwindfallen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;adjective : the feeling of dejection experienced after participating in a major coincidence without receiving acknowledgment, credit or reward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was crestwindfallen in three separate decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004 I coded printer drivers for a Silicon Valley company you've never heard of. Nights, sitting alone in the dark in my apartment, I looked up online how much money was going into my 401k. That was how I approximated a satisfying existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had just graduated. I didn't have a social life. The most exciting thing I found within that first year of working was drinking a certain &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/search?q=osmanthus+tea&amp;amp;client=ubuntu&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;biw=1680&amp;amp;bih=941&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CAgQ_AUoAmoVChMI6-nO3qHoxgIVECiICh0aeQ52"&gt;type of tea&lt;/a&gt;, and reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/search?q=dune&amp;amp;biw=1680&amp;amp;bih=941&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CAYQ_AUoAWoVChMIrdCRqcDmxgIVizWICh3rawVK#tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=dune+book"&gt;Dune&lt;/a&gt;. That was me in those days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I finished Dune, I was sad. I didn't want it to end. I wanted to know the Dune characters, personally. I wanted to be in the Dune setting more than I wanted to live my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few weeks, I tried to find Dune related music. I was looking for songs by popular artists written about the book. Were there any? Alas the Google searches, and Wikipedia entries weren't what they are today. All I found was some fan-fiction poetry with the disclaimer that what I reading was probably illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depressed, I loaded up my iPod. It was the one cool thing I bought before graduating. The Piece of Mind album by Iron Maiden was a grad school favorite. I lay on my bed, listening to it and staring at the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last song on the album, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_y3o4okKXMU"&gt;To Tame a Land&lt;/a&gt; was kind of slow. I usually skipped it. But at that moment, I was resigned to having nothing going on in my life. I was just some dude who was obsessed with Dune, both too nerdy and not nerdy enough for my environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I let the song play through its pedantic intro until finally the lyrics began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
He is the king of all the land/In the kingdom of the sands&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King. Sand. Was this song about Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
He is destined to be King/He rules over everything/In the land called... Banatude?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where was Banatude?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
On the sands so hot and dry/In a world called Arrakis&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, Arrakis? Suddenly my ears perked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
He is the Kwizatz Haderach/He is born of Caladan/And will take the Gom Jabbar&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy crap!!! This song was about Dune!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an incredible coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat up in my bed. I was in disbelief. I wanted to tell the world about what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But no one was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't know what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told a coworker about the experience. He was a major music geek who used to work in a record store. The only problem was that Iron Maiden was too mainstream for him to like out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I wanted to hear music about Dune,&amp;quot; I told him. &amp;quot;Then I happened to be listening to a 20 year old Iron Maiden album with a song about Dune on it! What are the odds of that?!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Iron Maiden? Aren't they the guys who play the same guitar riff over and over?&amp;quot; he replied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What? No. Anyways, it was super weird. I had spent a few weeks looking for a song about Dune. And then suddenly I was listening to it,&amp;quot; I told him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I'm sure you had heard the song before, and that's what caused you to listen to the album when you thought of Dune. That's not a very big deal.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a big deal to me. And all I got out of it was a lame conversation. I was very crestwindfallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 90s I visited the San Diego State campus. I was looking for my friend, David Braheny. All I knew was that he lived in a dorm there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked down a street, in the direction of some of the freshman dorms. A stocky, brown haired guy walked in my direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey, do you know where I can find David Braheny?&amp;quot; I asked. I was naive in those days, not truly comprehending how large a college campus was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy's mouth opened. He laughed. &amp;quot;That's... my roommate!&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy let me into the dorm. It was room 619. I remember that part because someone had taken a permanent marker to the 1. And I met David and I told him how I had somehow magically found his roommate walking down the street. That roommate told me I had greater odds of winning the lottery than running into him. It's true I participated in an incredible coincidence. But I did not win the lottery. I did not receive a reward. I was simply crestwindfallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom has a best friend. In the early 80s, my mom's best friend owned a jewelry store in a building in San Francisco, and as a child, I visited that jewelry store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second half of the 80s, my mom married my stepdad (note: who lived in Benicia, approximately 45 miles away from San Francisco). We discovered something amazing: my stepdad's brother (who also lived in Benicia, right across the street from my stepdad) had formerly rented an office in the same building in San Francisco as my mom's best friend. My mom's best friend actually knew my stepdad's family quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it turned out that due to an incredible coincidence, my stepdad and I shared more world experience than was otherwise apparent. We didn't need to be related before, to be connected before. And so that time, my feelings of being crestwindfallen were not that bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>This is The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>1984-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>ibowman</name></author><id>tag:ibowman.com,1984-01-01:theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up and decided to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought to write a technically oriented blog. And I started doing that. But I didn't like the look or functionality of any of the blog platforms I tried. I could have simply settled or compromised for the existing solutions, but that would not be very technically oriented, would it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then I thought to write a blog, as in coding one. And I got started on such a project, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy crap that was a lot of work for the average night or weekend. But the more I learned about templating languages, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs/dev/"&gt;Jinja&lt;/a&gt;, the more I realized I could create what I wanted by building a theme with a templating language, like Jinja... if only I could find a suitable platform to run that on top of. And one day, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;I found it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain"&gt;THE IRONED CURTAIN&lt;/a&gt;, where enemies become friends using 128 characters (TM). In addition to the blog, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/axonReaction/tic"&gt;TIC&lt;/a&gt; is a minimal Pelican theme written by yours truly, available for download on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click around on this blog and you'll see how fast everything loads. That is due to the distinct lack of the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;distracting ads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pointless graphics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inefficient flash code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;knee-jerk political pretense forgettable after 24 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meaningless lists that add no value to the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE IRONED CURTAIN uses the ASCII character set, as well as bold font-weight for hyperlinks. That's it. The entire thing could be transcribed by a hipster equipped with a manual typewriter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, this blog will be about technology, sometimes. It will more of the time be about details. It is in details that we are all unique, and I hope you will find the content here to be unique, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>