<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/</id><updated>1984-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>This is The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>1984-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>ibowman</name></author><id>tag:ibowman.com,1984-01-01:theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up and decided to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought to write a technically oriented blog. And I started doing that. Then I didn't like the look or functionality of any of the blog platforms I tried. And settling for what someone else has built before is not very technically oriented, is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I thought to write a blog, as in coding one. And I got started on such a project, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy crap that was a lot of work for the average night or weekend. But the more I learned about templating languages, like Jinja, the more I realized I could create what I wanted by building a theme with a templating language, like Jinja... if only I found an existing platform to run that on top of. And one day, I found it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing THE IRONED CURTAIN, the world's first 7-bit website, where enemies become friends using 128 characters (TM). In addition to a blog, THE IRONED CURTAIN is a minimal Pelican theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click around and you'll see how fast everything loads, due to the distinct lack of the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;distracting ads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pointless graphics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inefficient flash code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;knee-jerk political pretense, completely forgettable after 24 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meaningless lists that add no value to the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE IRONED CURTAIN uses the original ASCII character set, as well as bold font-weight (e.g. for hyperlinks). That's it. The entire thing could be transcribed by a hipster equipped with a manual typewriter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In THE IRONED CURTAIN I will cover a number of technical topics. I hope when you read this blog you find the perspective to be unique.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>