<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/</id><updated>1984-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>This is The Ironed Curtain</title><link href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>1984-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>ibowman</name></author><id>tag:ibowman.com,1984-01-01:theironedcurtain/this-is-the-ironed-curtain.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up and decided to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought to write a technically oriented blog. And I started doing that. But I didn't like the look or functionality of any of the blog platforms I tried. I could have simply settled or compromised for the existing solutions, but that would not be very technically oriented, would it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then I thought to write a blog, as in coding one. And I got started on such a project, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy crap that was a lot of work for the average night or weekend. But the more I learned about templating languages, like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs/dev/"&gt;Jinja&lt;/a&gt;, the more I realized I could create what I wanted by building a theme with a templating language, like Jinja... if only I could find a suitable platform to run that on top of. And one day, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;I found it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ibowman.com/theironedcurtain"&gt;THE IRONED CURTAIN&lt;/a&gt;, where enemies become friends using 128 characters (TM). In addition to the blog, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/axonReaction/tic"&gt;TIC&lt;/a&gt; is a minimal Pelican theme written by yours truly, available for download on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click around on this blog and you'll see how fast everything loads. That is due to the distinct lack of the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;distracting ads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pointless graphics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;inefficient flash code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;knee-jerk political pretense forgettable after 24 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;meaningless lists that add no value to the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE IRONED CURTAIN uses the ASCII character set, as well as bold font-weight for hyperlinks. That's it. The entire thing could be transcribed by a hipster equipped with a manual typewriter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, this blog will be about technology, sometimes. It will more of the time be about details. It is in details that we are all unique, and I hope you will find the content here to be unique, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>